Good afternoon.
2 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
And everyone welcome to the Cisco engagement, we will discuss the assurance dashboard today, take some Q and a.
3 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
And wanted you to be aware that a, and Sasha, and I are working on some troubleshooting documentation now, we can send it as a package to you before our next meeting. Okay.
4 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
So, with that session is yours.
5 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Yeah, okay. So, um, I think, um.
6 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
As we discuss in our previous call, uh, we actually went over the short and dashboard and.
7 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And different areas through which we can monitor the network devices and troubleshoot the issues. And I think the takeaway was, uh, next time to go, uh, into your own DNA center and, uh, look for some more, uh, issues, examples and some, uh, troubleshooting examples. So.
8 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Anyone who can share the screen. Probably we can use your DNA center to just go and look things around. And probably while exploring the different, uh, pages and the dashboard. If you have questions, I can, I'm happy to answer or probably, I can.
9 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Look for some areas where I can use to, um.
10 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
To go, dig deep and provide you more information about it right?
11 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Unfortunately machine, the lab is not up ready up and up and running yet. Um, I dunno. Uh, Robbie or Leon. If you wanna W, W1 of, you can share either a danger. For instance. Um, obviously, we're not going to deploy anything. It's just going to poke around so we can choose the chain.
12 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
The decision is, it gets a better idea on the deployment grander. I know it's not production. So and its response times are pretty quick. I don't know if you guys agree with it. Um, so we can go a little bit about, um.
13 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
What's being deployed and boundary is not fully deployed yet. It's actually the best that we have in a lot of features with. I don't know if you guys want to follow that route or or, um.
14 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Between if you have, um, in your in your lab, uh, configure, uh, your SDA fabric, we can also use your blog as well. I mean, whatever works for you.
15 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
I think, yeah, so, in my lab, I have a very limited, like, um, issues that I can show and areas like, where, um, I can see how how DNA can help and troubleshooting. And that's where I thought like, of using your DNS center. Uh.
16 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
To see, I mean, because there you will be, you will be able to correlate it with your existing environment and see what information you're looking for out and how the neck is helping. So, I'm okay to share my but you will have.
17 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Probably you probably already. Yeah, you guys prefer to to share 1 of you.
18 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
1 of your deployments and and you can guys can walk them through or ask questions. Okay. I want to see how this vxlan or or this configured.
19 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
We, we can, we can use the, your your.
20 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Uh, deployment as the, the, the base for the, the overview I don't know it's up to you guys.
21 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
I know the lab is not ready yet, because that what that was the original intention. You're having your lab somewhat ready already, but, um, yeah.
22 "Ravi" (3362501120)
I am whichever works better. That's fine. Um, I'm not sure how how much calendar was built so, maybe I can I.
23 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Roger, it's, it's almost fully built already and but I'm not in production, but, uh, we have some issues with it. As a matter of fact, it might be it might be a good example to.
24 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
To poke around and see, uh, things so.
25 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Can you share I mean, or 1 of you guys, can you share your screen and log into it? It's better to.
26 "Alian Alfonso" (2074447872)
I can not share my screen right now.
27 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
And share your screen right now. Okay. That's someone.
28 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
That's all my screen. Let me check.
29 "Ravi" (3362501120)
Give me 3rd.
30 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Are we okay, so I will just like the plan is like to go.
31 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Into the fabric and, uh, just go, like, how to do a fabric deployment or going into the, the.
32 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Has been deployed already right remember this team will not be deploying new fabrics. This team will be troubleshooting existing deployments right? That's.
33 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
That's right. Yeah. Um, so I thought like, okay, so that by having.
34 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, your daddy in the center.
35 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
We can see more issues PT or fabric or non fabric issues.
36 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Like, uh, different flavors of issues, we can see your DNA center and, uh, that would give us an idea. Everyone an idea like, okay, what type of issues you can see in DNA center, how they can help you in troubleshooting or what are some of the.
37 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Areas you can start a new start seeing from DNA or related issues.
38 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
I mean, it's definitely a, there's a dedicated troubleshooting session plan. Probably sometime next week, we can do that. Then there I will actually go from, like, bottom to top approach of, like, troubleshooting the SDA issue. So.
39 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, that is a dedicated session. Definitely. I'm going to.
40 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Do on troubleshooting. Okay. Perfect.
41 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
All right and I'm searching, I share with you for the document with, uh.
42 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
The data flows and the different that they have deployed, right?
43 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
So, we can poke up I mean, we, we can grab a couple of those.
44 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Well, and and walk them through in DNA center, probably log into some of the switches and the controllers and border and so they can get to see what's being deployed to the fabric. That's the intention. The intention is to pretty much.
45 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Map the deployment to, uh, the concepts that they've learned, uh.
46 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
On the training, right? And this is how you're tracking employees, how you track list, you track your external board, or these are your advertise to your external route.
47 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Those kinds of things, so you give him like a sure. Good.
48 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Will packet if you will right?
49 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
I agree. Yep. Cool. Perfect. Thank you.
50 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Will you be able to share your screen or? Yeah.
51 "Ravi" (3362501120)
I'll share it. I'm working on the login credentials. Give me 1 minute. Perfect perfect.
52 "Ravi" (3362501120)
Okay, let me share my screen. I just logged in.
53 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Do you mind? Yeah, let me let me see.
54 "Ravi" (3362501120)
Give me 3rd, let me share the exact monitor. Okay. Okay. I.
55 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Able to see the DNA I'm not sure if that's the right. Yeah. Can you.
56 "Ravi" (3362501120)
You see it now. Yeah.
57 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, let me just request for the control hub. Okay, sure.
58 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, let me just go into the home page.
59 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
I see that showing.
60 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
To get the update 20,370.
61 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, and I see on the homepage, I can see there are a lot of issues being imported.
62 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
If you want, I can directly go into the dashboard. 1st.
63 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Sure, let's do like, we can start getting used to the, uh.
64 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
I believe that provides.
65 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Let's take a look at the top 10 issues what you're seeing right now.
66 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, so yeah, there are 3 people issues. I can see here last 24 hours uh, 1 is like, switch unreachable. So.
67 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
In the switch unreachable. I see there are a lot of different switches, which are showing unreachable. They're all 3530 or 60 platforms. Now when they are showing unreachable. Are they like decommissioned? Or is the site down or under.
68 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
It's good. It's good. That is showing them this information.
69 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
All right, but remember, this is the vessel that is going to be built so it's, it's expected expected someone's on stability in the network. So it could be that the, the is shutting down sections of the network, right?
70 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
But it's good to see the begin to see this. Right they get to see the visibility that the engagement on this front, right?
71 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
But, like I said, it's not nothing to be concerned about this specific fabric right now. It's still not in production. Yet it's been built will be in production. I believe sometime next week or the week after. So.
72 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, so that's the deck 9 where, uh, the this is being built a network is being built there. That's why this.
73 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Yeah, it looks like Omar so it looks like tech 9 is the 1 having a problem.
74 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
9 is mostly all the switches are in the date 9.
75 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Hello.
76 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, so.
77 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Fabric facing port channel connectivity. Let's take a look at this 1.
78 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
It says that the status is down on the edge node fabric facing port channel. That's the port serial number. And this is again, the deck 9 these are from the different decks, different 836 911 and these are different devices. And the switch is a 9,410.
79 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And you can see where that issue is.
80 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Now, this switch, it says that this particular interface portal, 18 on fabricate node.
81 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Is actually showing down now, here we see that, uh, other, uh, other than just showing into showing that issue now, we know the device name and when the issue, uh, occurred, but is giving us some suggested actions to, uh, fix that issue. So, 1st is like to verify that the port is error free.
82 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And it also tells us, like, how, and what commands you can run to see whether the port is error free and are now other than just giving you the interfaces or the commands. You can also exit directly execute those commands from DNA center.
83 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Dina can log in and get and fetch output of the app. So you don't need to jump back and forth from your DNS entity and network devices. You can directly execute those commands from DNS enter and see.
84 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Whether that what is the issue with that? Right? So you see that the port channel.
85 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Here, uh, I see the portion it's showing up.
86 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Yeah, so I don't know why it's complaining.
87 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Yeah, it looks like the issue has been resolved. Okay.
88 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Take a look, let's take some other steps.
89 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Physical interfaces and the portion is up. I think the interface is also. Yup.
90 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, so a status on edge note fabric.
91 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Please import 2018. what we can also do is.
92 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
You can go into the device.
93 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Hmm.
94 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And take a look at this, help out those interfaces.
95 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
And the, this the fabric is.
96 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
And the other side of the world is basically neatly. Right? And sometimes the uplink bandwidth is.
97 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Limited so response response could be slow.
98 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Oh, okay. I got it. Okay.
99 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Yeah, thanks for telling me.
100 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
I know that was going to be a blackout.
101 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Today, okay.
102 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Well, that was yesterday was yesterday. Okay. Yeah.
103 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Oh, sorry. So this, um, issue was, I think initially occurred on October 12.
104 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And was not supported on November.
105 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
9, so this is 3 agenda is the update that is showing.
106 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Down here.
107 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Yes.
108 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, let's take a look at the interfaces.
109 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Oh.
110 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
I think you can filter, right? If you filter you type on the filter to just.
111 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Hello? Hello? Hello?
112 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
There you go. Okay.
113 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, yeah, here operational started showing up. Okay so this.
114 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
There's another up link, I think this portion is showing up, but I see see, here it is showing down.
115 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Remember that these are dual home.
116 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Oh, good. 1.
117 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
So, 4 channels and 1 more time, because this is going to go into a VSS, the the VSS, right?
118 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Yeah, it's so.
119 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Is it a single channel you have 2 channels? I think this is for channel.
120 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
All right, so, yeah, that's the only the only thing should be, right?
121 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, then I think there's a issues no longer.
122 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Valid because the portion is our, the status is showing up here.
123 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Oh, yeah, go back to the little green thing.
124 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
So, it's Sean. Okay right there. It's, uh, it's joined that, uh.
125 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Think so right now is for 10 so the.
126 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
I think that there said that it was down up until 3 something PM, wasn't it?
127 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
On the air, it said that from October something to November.
128 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
It looks like it's been up for a while now right?
129 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
I see, uh, I mean.
130 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
The 1, it was.
131 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
It shows that the no data, if it is down, it would have been shown as I read.
132 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Um.
133 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
The other thing could be like, depending on the number of, uh, the member of the port channel, if 1 of the physical interfaces down, that could be.
134 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
The reason it is showing as a down interface, but let me also check 1 more thing.
135 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
If I go under the inventory.
136 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Do you remember the tone? What was it?
137 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And let me just quickly switch back and copy the name.
138 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
3.
139 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Entry.
140 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So this is another view through which you can see the number of boards and the ports just showing up and down. So, let me just quickly change here.
141 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
To port channel, it's gonna tell us number for.
142 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
I probably probably do it on the supervisory elements are calling this voice.
143 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
All right.
144 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
18, I don't see that here. Oh.
145 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
See, there I see 11,716 and 27th and 22.
146 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Can you do your own commands run commands show it? Yeah.
147 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
On all the hubs, the port channel 1 is the port channel between that and the order.
148 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Okay, and then, uh, all the extended nodes, let's start their core channels above that.
149 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Okay, yeah, that's that's a PhD unfortunately. So that goes down to an extent a note.
150 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
But it's up now, so.
151 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Yeah, even on the insurance, I noticed that we are showing up.
152 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Just in the issues we noticed that, uh, was showing as an issue.
153 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Let me open that up.
154 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
But this is a good time, right? It's good. You guys get to see, um.
155 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
The short I can get to see how you can you can track.
156 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Thanks, that's the whole intention of this call, right?
157 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Yeah, and I'm not sure if you, if you've set up any kind of notification, but from DNA center, you can set up like, the events notification. If you would like to receive, let's say, the P1 type issues like an email notification of type issues. Uh, you can do that to it's easy.
158 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
That way you don't need to come to DNA center dashboard and look for the.
159 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Latest issues, you will get notified every time and there is an issue new issue pops up and.
160 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
I see the other workshops as well.
161 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Different switches and zooming guys connected to the extended.
162 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Let's see interface connecting network devices down.
163 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
These are some of the interfaces that are showing down.
164 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
I mean, the very 1st thing that we need to check is, like, whether issues latest or when it was last occurred. Right? So, for an example, the 1st issue that says that 5 K3 slides users to, um, from this.
165 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Is the location of the switch.
166 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Id, it's a 9,410 switch, but this issue was reported on November 8.
167 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, the last post occurred in November in the last record is number 8. so that means the issue may not be valid anymore. Uh, this was reported, um.
168 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Might be up now.
169 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, every time when we are looking into the issue, I think, better to look into the time as well, when the issue was last occurred, if it is like, some time back, then the issue may not be valid.
170 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, fabric, device, connectivity overlay.
171 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, let me just quickly go and validate whether those interfaces up or down.
172 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
What's the current status? Right? So.
173 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Here, and I think this is 1 of the questions, right which I got like, that machine reasoning for some of the issues, or help you using that machine briefing engine. So let's say if you want to get this issue checked.
174 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Now, instead of having those static troubleshooting steps, you have this machine reasoning engine.
175 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Using this you can see.
176 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
What could be the problem here and I can help you to identify that as a problem.
177 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Um, it's going to just collect the outputs and give you the results. And also the conclusion, what is the problem here when this interfaces.
178 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, so this is completed, um, now, if you go into the conclusion tab.
179 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, so here we can like, now using this, we can clearly say that identify that this port is currently up now, uh, it was, it went down, but as of now, the sport is up now, if you want to see when that port went down again, the same way, we can go into the device 360 view where we looked into that specific.
180 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
For that will give you the detail of when it was down. And when it came back up.
181 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
All right, so this is easy. Like to see if that issue is, um.
182 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Is valid, or not this clearly say that the port is up and so no further analysis needed.
183 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Part of this issue now 1 more thing let's say if you see that, uh, issue that type of issue.
184 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Is coming and it's resolved you can also manually resolve the issues by clicking on the action and go and click on results. So that that issue will not pop up again. If you think that that interface may may go down again.
185 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And you want to see that as an issue that you can leave it as it is, this will be auto is or after some time, it will be removed from the DNS issues list.
186 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, let me take a look at a couple more.
187 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Public device connectivity is is Co located fabric, border and control plane. This particular device loss connectivity to the DNS server.
188 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And the virtual network DMZ VPN so.
189 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Using this, we can clearly say that at some point.
190 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Under that DMZ, virtual network.
191 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
That, uh, board and control plane load, lost the connectivity to the DNS server.
192 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Now, let's take a look at that issue if you can get more information by looking at going into the.
193 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
The detail of that so here you see that now.
194 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
It says that this is the border control plane load. It could not reach the DNS server and the eyepiece 107,524 using the DMZ. So, from the DMZ VPN DNS server was unreachable.
195 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Problem details and the problem details it highlights that.
196 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
This is the overlay virtual network and, uh, this is, um.
197 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And your DNS was showing down and starting from this time frame.
198 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
November 9220pmescalating, it's.
199 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And here, it gives you the destination information of.
200 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Different, um, virtual networks.
201 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
If we go after looking into the problem details, if you want, we can go into the suggested actions and let's look for the possible troubleshooting steps to figure out what the problem is.
202 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Servers on the table, so the very 1st step is verify whether the DNS server is up on our.
203 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Verify the configurations compliant on the network device you want to learn more about it. You just see whether your network, or you can do a board and control plane load has the DNS server information, the domain name and your list contributions there.
204 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
We have that out to the DNS server so using this command.
205 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, I mean, when it is giving you the steps, it is also telling you the commands as well that you can run to figure out whether we have, we lost the route for the DNS server. What? And also the uplink.
206 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Routing each ability we have that on that. Right? So it does it's like to check the.
207 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Layer 3, routing protocol, each ability, or the neighborhood from the upstream device and at the very last, if you are enabled to resolve that issue by yourself, then you can contact Cisco tag for that.
208 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, you can also open cases.
209 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Directly from DNA center as well right? So there's a link shortcut link where.
210 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
This is contact support if I click on it, that is gonna take me to the tax support page where I can open a case. If this is something which you think that requires some additional troubleshooting.
211 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And tech that needs to help or techniques to jump. In that case, you can open a case with the tech team. But before that, you can, uh, perform all the troubleshooting steps, which is mentioned here and see if that is if 1 of that is going to give you a clue uh, what, what was the problem? Exactly.
212 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
I have a question about that error though.
213 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Bring that error back up, please.
214 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Okay, the the way that it's worded.
215 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Now, does it think that about 75 dot 50 dot 24.
216 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Is in the DMZ.
217 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Or is it saying that it can't reach that from the DMZ.
218 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
It says it cannot read from DMZ VPN. The way I read it says this is my control and border ignored. It cannot reach the DNS server.
219 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, the DNS server in the virtual network of right? So, from the DMZ, like the DNS server, the design DNS server, which is.
220 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Unreachable well, that's my design servers. Not reachable from our DMZ.
221 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, and is that is that server configured on the on the device.
222 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Is configured on the on the on boarding control thing.
223 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
It is, because the border control note is in the what we call our green zone.
224 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Which is in in the main.
225 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
The management.
226 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, so this is by design, then you can probably ignore our resolve this issue.
227 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
I think because of this configuration, Dean, I guess, uh, giving us this information that this DNS server is not reachable from the but if it is that way, it has to be that way, then we can simply resolve this. And so that we don't get highlighted of this issue because we know that this is, this is as per design.
228 "Gordon Montgomery" (4276751872)
Okay.
229 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, so, let me look for some more issues. No activity and bulkier radio for your.
230 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And the different different AP, we are seeing the similar.
231 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Is that from 90 for 24 94,480.
232 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Let me take a look and see what it's trying to say on this by gear radio. You have not seen any receipt packet activity for the past 60 minutes.
233 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So so, okay, what it is highlighting is, like, in the area, where, with this particular AP, based on the 5 gigahertz radio, we did not see that as an activity. So it's by default. I mean, if you think there is something again, as part of the design, probably we can adjust this type of issue.
234 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
When the issue setting and how we want to see that, but.
235 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Yeah, is notifying it's like on this particular radio, we are not seeing any clients getting connected. Um, so it's, it's reporting that as a, as an issue.
236 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
But, yeah, you can definitely go into the issues setting up the thing that the time that we need to increase or.
237 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
We do not want to see these type of issues because the way the page you may not see, uh, users frequently in that area. Then.
238 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And you can simply turn that off.
239 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Previous service, not responding is a particular issue is not responding to requests being made from the network device is.
240 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
There are 2 different issues from 2 different devices.
241 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
There might already got 60 AP, which is.
242 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And what is telling us, like, we just need to ensure that we have the connectivity to the server.
243 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Technical connectivity between the radio server, and then it will do it and show the port is open.
244 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
If I send you, the need to be dumped diagnostic tool to check the signal request from the time.
245 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And isolated logs messages regions for a lack of reply.
246 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, again, this like a communication between the and the radio server and.
247 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
This particular time frame this device on these ports.
248 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
It's not responding for the triple a requests or the radius requests. That's why this issue is being.
249 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
The disconnected from the.
250 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, have you noticed or this particular access point disconnected from the.
251 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And this is the named the switch it was connected to and this port, it was connected to.
252 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
This issue of starts occurred on November 8.
253 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Let's see if that is, it is up or down right now.
254 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
The connectivity, I don't see anything here or map. It's gonna show us like a place for on the floor map somewhere. He can see where exactly that is placed.
255 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Who are the impacted who is currently know.
256 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Impacted location it is the location where the place.
257 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And so this production is to check.
258 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Inventory page, and this is managed by DNA center not be there to inventory. Otherwise we'll not be able to run commands on the following. So, just production. The 1st, it is telling us like to see if the switch where the is connected, that switches in the inventory or not.
259 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Um, and then once we have that inventory, then we can execute this command.
260 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Assume the switches there in the inventory that that's there then we can check the CDP neighbor on the still up.
261 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And connect to the switch, and the host name has not changed if they has reached out to the default value.
262 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Indicate that the had lots of configuration.
263 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Take the CDP neighbor detailed commands.
264 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Verify the AP has valid if it does not have the then we need to check the dscp server. So on could be because AP lost. Um.
265 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Or if you got restarted and did not get an IC address from the server.
266 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Let's check whether the view is enabled on the switch is again, all these commands that you're going to run there on the switch.
267 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And check the condition of the copper table by running like that to ensure that the, the cable is not faulty, it's gonna run the tdr diagnostic just to ensure.
268 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
The board where the safety is connected to the cable is not faulty because of that. It is, uh, showing and.
269 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And fix the reserve and use the partner tool to verify with the day he can communicate with the WSC via. So, that's where the capital communication.
270 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, if the AP is physically up, and some are loss of connectivity to the wireless controller, and this is that, that tells us to ensure the AP and even if he has an AP address, and it still does not show up in the controller then we need to validate whether the has the capital communication, or these ports are open between the AP to the controller.
271 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
To get registered on the wireless controller now, then the reboot AP so that it can rejoin that and at the very last contact attack, if you cannot resolve the issue. So, for these type of issue, there are different steps highlighted here. So.
272 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Again, if you want to, can you.
273 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
You can then these commands and see the outputs and see if there is up or down.
274 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
All right, these are the same steps you can perform to troubleshoot the issues.
275 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
So, if in case, let's say the team, I don't know, we're gonna have a deeper troubleshooting session, starting next week. Right? But what I'm understanding here is in case, the team gets a call, let's say wireless user users complaining about slowest right? You're saying that assurance.
276 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Dashboards should be the 1st place we should check for a hint of what could potentially be wrong. Right?
277 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Yep.
278 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, um.
279 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Was that question to me, I, I was saying that so basically what we're saying here is that, let's say a cold content, right for the support team, saying whatever there's.
280 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Wireless users are complaining about slowness. That's that's a typical 1 that we all love because it's, it's very hard to pinpoint. Right so this could be the result of many, many factors. Right? So what we're saying is basically the assurance dashboard that dashboards should be the 1st.
281 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Point where the 1st step where we check for.
282 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Problems right yeah, absolutely. I mean, so let's say when the wireless users is having the poor experiences having the wireless issues, we would like to figure out whether that's because of.
283 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
The, like, the expenses that issue is specific to that particular user, or all the users who are in the network, or who are connected to the, that, particularly they are having a similar experience. So, I would definitely say that Dina would be the 1st place to start exploring it and.
284 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Yeah, I mean, I was showing into the Shannon, but those type of issues, and we see that. Okay. 1 user is complaining about it and we know that this particular site or the user must be in DNA center, and you can actually jump into the DNA center. Go to the global search.
285 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
But and see if you know, the of the, the end of the user or.
286 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
The host name of the user's machine, uh, which are like, through, which we can identify we can just look for it.
287 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And see, how how his experience has been in the network.
288 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
From last couple of hours, uh, can we, we look for a new point to see if we.
289 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
To see that. Uh, sure. Yeah. Let me quickly. See if I go to the client section and say, if I pick a client here.
290 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Perfect these are my wireless clients, right? I can see the Microsoft workstation, Android and iPad.
291 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
All right, so let's say if I pick the 1st user, this wireless user.
292 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
I can see that user is currently on boarded in the network. The current health is showing 10 so just looking or going into the 360. I can see what's the latest? What is the.
293 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Recent experience customers having right now so it's onboarding is past the association. Onboarding time. How much time it we can from a user point of view. We can see the and here.
294 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Even like the IP, which Laurie is sitting which location is on, which is connected to what band is on all that information we can see here. So, if we, if the user is complaining, let's say, by.
295 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Um, if that is, that has an idea that similar like this.
296 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
I can just.
297 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Use that to go into the global search and look for that. And that is going to tell me.
298 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
About that user. All right so I can.
299 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Click on that client 360 and we'll definitely land into this page right here. I can see where. Exactly the user is physically.
300 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Place right and so here, and even for the upstream devices, let's say the user is having to your experience could be it could be, because the the environment it could be because of the AP wireless controller. Anything. Right? So, here in the onboarding section, we can see everything is showing green, right? The dscp triple.
301 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Is onboarding association? Everything is good. Even the upstream network devices. The AP and the controller their health is also good.
302 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Currently, this particular AP has only 1 client.
303 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
If that, but if the has more clients, then if we can also see the list of all those clients and their health as well.
304 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So this is a good correlation that we can see if that particular, uh, user, let's say if his health score is coming up I'd say 4 or 5, because.
305 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, because of some issues, right then to the upstream device, we can see how the other clients how many other clients are connected to that particular AP and what their health score is, is it because, uh, the network device or because the, the user itself we are noticing that if you are, if it is like a specific.
306 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
That issue, or the network issue, right? So that can help us to identify that again. Even we are going to help us, like.
307 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
That particular user is helping, or having challenges in the onboarding authentication Association.
308 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Right. We can see all of them in the event career section here.
309 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Detail information this under the detail information is connectivity and can give us a very good understanding. Like, how is our experience has been mostly when we see a customer complaints, or the user complaints that he's having slow.
310 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, slow, wireless or poor wireless connectivity, then this can give us a complete, uh, visibility that okay what's his? And s, and our values audit? Are they.
311 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And then the threshold, so he's crossing the thresholds there.
312 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, using this, we can, we can look for the individual, uh, clients issue, wireless or wired and fine, but we can look into that those issues in DNA center. So I will definitely I would say, like, to have, um.
313 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
As the 1st point of investigation would help and I, I don't know I've talked about this intelligent packet capture or not.
314 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
But this is some advanced assurance capabilities that offers so traditionally.
315 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, like for our wireless users, it was very hard. It used to be very hard to do a packet capture for those wireless users. So now with this intelligent packet capture, we can, if we are, we are looking for some serious issues for specific client.
316 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
We can then the packet capture for those clients and, um, we can see, like.
317 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
What exactly are the challenges for, in, in the deal that we can run the packet captures for that specific client, and can download that. We kept files and investigate okay. For his onboarding for his data package. Uh, what, what other issues? So, you can also run the packet capture for your, uh, individual wireless.
318 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Violent crimes using DNA.
319 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
And that captures from from the.
320 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, I mean, uh, or so, this is from the AP AP 1. okay.
321 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
From the yeah, the good thing is like this intelligent packet capture.
322 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, AP communicates with directly whenever we run this packet capture whatever architecture happens, they directly, they don't go through the wireless controller or anything directly like, AP gives all the information directly back to the DNA center. And the good thing is, like, when I run this.
323 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
It, uh, I mean, it's easy I can just simply click on this the packet capture.
324 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, when I started, we will all see, like, the, the live activities from that end user.
325 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Like, his onboarding or any, any attempts he is doing let's say he's trying to get onboarded and our challenges using this. You can see what is, what is that end users uh, seeing right now.
326 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Right so, and these, like, uh, they will show up in different colors. So, if he's getting, let's say his triple is getting timed out or dscp servers responses.
327 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Uh, time getting timed out, right? We will see all those as a like a red.
328 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Marks or different colors, you can see what exactly are the problems there.
329 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Like, a remote remote span from.
330 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Pretty much, right? Yeah. So what what is doing is AP, basically, uh, for that particular implant, it is.
331 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Getting all the information and giving it directly back to DNA center.
332 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Correct, yeah, and this download button actually has like, whatever packet capture we are doing. Uh, when I click on run, it will start running it. And after that, uh, I can stop it and whatever packets you have captured you can just simply download it. It will be downloaded in a PDF file.
333 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And we can use that to to see that in a, in a workshop or something, if you want. But but even when we run the packet captures, so you will see all these graphs will start populating. So we can see some good data. Mm. Hmm. When we start doing that packet capture.
334 "Ravi" (3362501120)
Or the end user, and we do this for a wired as well or.
335 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
It's just for wireless. Yeah. Good question. Uh, currently, it is only for wireless. Okay. Now.
336 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Having the ability to trigger a packet capture on the.
337 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Node is only available for a.
338 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Right now, switching is everything yeah, that is true. So there in the packet capture there are 2 types of packet capture get date, right? When we call it as a partial packet caption, full packet girlfriend, it depends on the type of AP you have in your environment. Right? So all the, the high end models, like 934,800 or 38 hundred's escaping.
339 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Are capable of doing the full packet capture and when I say full target capture means, you can not only just see the onboarding events.
340 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
But you can also see the actual data traffic then client is sending.
341 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
So, that full package capture will give you that complete visibility. The partial is that where you will get on the, uh, the captures of onboarding events?
342 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Okay, so if your end user is having challenges and the onboarding that don't need that, that you can capture using the partial bucket captured.
343 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
And, yeah, I mean, if you're interested, if you would like to see, I don't want to turn it on on your environment, when you have your users, but I can try my lab and show you around and how this can be helpful.
344 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
This packet intelligent capture, so we call them like these intelligent packet captures and sensors and advanced ai network and these are some advanced wireless charging use cases um, which gives additional visibility .
345 "Sachin Sharma" (168054016)
Additional steps to troubleshoot your issues, which you cannot resolve from your standard assurance tools that we have here like the issues list and troubleshooting steps. If you cannot figure out the, the issues from them, then you can use these tools to, to understand more about that.
346 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Any question guys.
347 "Ravi" (3362501120)
No, I am. I'm good.
348 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Okay, Tim managed.
349 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
To the hour, we need to build a plan here or okay to go with the next topic. Do we have any more questions?
350 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
Or do we have any do we need more time?
351 "Ravi" (3362501120)
Yeah, I have another engagement at exactly. 5. um, I need to attend and also we have less audience today. So can we continue in.
352 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
The next session from here, that is absolutely fine with us. Okay, so, Sasha, this is.
353 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Picking up for the next time, right Robin, I think tonya's question was more of a, you guys want to spend more time on assurance, uh, dashboards, or you guys want to move to the next topic. And, um, so if possible, Robbie, I mean, uh, touch base with, with Alicia and review the, the.
354 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
The 3 sessions sure. And I'll get back to us, so we can build upon and say, we're building a like, a package library for for you guys for the next topic for publishing. So, but if you guys like Tennessee, if you guys want to spend more time here, want to see, um.
355 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
The some of these tools like machine said, he has some of them on his lab and we can, we can showcase in there as well. Right? So, it's up to you. I mean, you guys, you guys guide us. I mean, you got to spend more time or you want to.
356 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
The next topic remember, this session is completely for you. It is to.
357 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
Help you get to the next step if you feel like you need more time and any 1 of these.
358 "Ravi" (3362501120)
Let us know sure.
359 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
Okay, so we'll build a.
360 "Aian Denis" (3346593280)
Plan for next week.
361 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
You very much for your time. Sounds good. Thank you. So much guys. Thank you. So.
362 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
So, you guys next week, thank you. Bye. Bye. Bye. Bye.
363 "Tania Alves" (1571568640)
Hi.